proline.ca 2004-12-15

# OLGC.ca: Privacy

Last updated: January 28, 2004. 

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, please call 

1-800-387-0098.

The Ontario Lottery and Gaming Corporation (OLGC) is committed to respecting your privacy and protecting your personal information. This Privacy Statement explains the current information management practices at our Web sites.

The handling of all personal information by Government of Ontario organizations (including the OLGC) is governed by the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (FIPPA).

This Web site Privacy Policy contains detailed information about the following:

  1. What information of yours does OLGC collect?
  2. How does OLGC collect personal information?
  3. What are "cookies" and does OLGC use them?
  4. Who is collecting the information?
  5. How does OLGC use the information collected?
  6. Does OLGC share the information that is collected?
  7. How can you access, edit or delete your information?
  8. What type of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?

This Web site Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time so please check back periodically. 

External Links Disclaimer: In some cases, we link to other sites created and maintained by other public and/or private sector organizations. We provide these links solely for your information and convenience. When you link to an outside Web site, you are leaving the OLGC Web site and our information management policies no longer apply. 

**1\. What information of yours do OLGC Web sites collect?**  
When you browse or download information from OLGC Web sites, our servers automatically collect limited amounts of standard information for traffic monitoring and statistical purposes. The information is analyzed for operational trends, performance, and for ways to improve our sites. The OLGC cannot identify you from this information. Example information includes, but is not limited to, the following: 

  * Internet Protocol (IP) addresses of the computers being used to access our sites; 
  * the operating systems and the types and versions of browsers used to access our sites; 
  * the Internet Service Providers used by visitors to our sites; 
  * the dates and times users access our sites; 
  * the pages visited; and 
  * the names and sizes of files requested. 

In addition to this anonymous information, OLGC may also collect information that is about an identifiable individual, referred to within as personal information. Personal information includes information that tells us specifically who you are, such as your name and email address. 

Back To Top

**2\. How does OLGC collect personal information?**  
Personal information is gathered when you voluntarily register within one of OLGC's Web sites. This includes: 

  * submitting a comment, question or request via e-mail, 
  * requesting an e-mail alert such as Winning Numbers, 
  * entering a contest or filling out a survey online; or, 
  * requesting a product/service requiring personal information such as address, phone number, and credit card (e.g. Lotto Advance e-mail subscription request) 

In each case, any personal information you provide will be used to respond to your message and/or provide you with the requested service or product. 

Any personal information provided is collected pursuant to the Ontario Lottery and Gaming Corporation Act, 1999. For further information contact an OLGC representative at 1-800-387-0098. 

Back To Top

**3\. What are "cookies" and does OLGC use them?**  
A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a Web site to the hard drive of your computer. This unique number identifies your browser, but not the individual, whenever you visit one of OLGC's Web sites. These cookies will not let a Web site know any personal information about you, such as your name and address. Since these cookies are only text files, they cannot run on your computer, search your computer for other information or transmit any information to anyone. Cookies are used on many major Web sites. Many browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can reset your browser either to notify you when you have received a cookie, or to refuse to accept cookies. 

To help serve you better, OLGC uses two types of cookies: session cookies (temporary) and persistent cookies (longer-term continuing use). Session cookies are used to support on-line feedback/discussion, forms and registration and our sports payout calculator functionality. They are used only during your online session and expire when you close your browser. Without session cookies, moving around our Web sites would be much slower. Persistent cookies are stored on your computer's hard drive for some length of time. They are usually used if you want us to remember information about your Web preferences (e.g. language preference) and passwords for automatic log-in purposes. 

Back To Top

**4\. Who is collecting the information?**  
When you provide personal information at any OLGC Web site, that information is collected by OLGC. OLGC may offer sweepstakes, contests or promotions on OLGC Web sites. These sweepstakes, contests or promotions may be operated by third parties on behalf of OLGC, in which case personal information may be collected by such third party, or disclosed to such third party by OLGC. If you do not want to have OLGC share your personal information for such purposes, you can choose not to opt-in to the sweepstakes, contest or promotion. 

Back To Top

**5\. How does the OLGC use the information it collects?**  
Any personal information you provide to OLGC when registering for products and services at any of OLGC's Web sites is maintained by OLGC and OLGC's authorized web hosting provider, unless specifically stated otherwise. Furthermore, only certain employees of OLGC have access to personal information submitted through OLGC Web sites. OLGC requests information from its users so that they can enjoy customized experiences across OLGC Web sites. OLGC may use the information it collects as follows: 

  * To offer its users the ability in the future to customize or personalize content on OLGC Web sites. 
  * To deliver products and services requested by consumers. 

OLGC also uses the anonymous, aggregate data to perform statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behaviour of our Web site visitors. Without such data, it would be difficult for us to know what the most popular areas of the OLGC Web sites are, and it would be difficult for us to change and update the content and services appropriately. OLGC also uses such data to monitor and improve the operation of our Web sites and to maintain the quality of the products and services available through our Web sites. 

If you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion through OLGC's Web sites, OLGC will use the personal information you provided to contact you in the event you win. All such OLGC contest entry forms will provide a way for a consumer to opt-in to any communications that is not related to awarding prizes for the promotion. Any information you provide will not be shared with such third parties unless you agree through the appropriate consent box on the entry form. If you enter a contest, you may be asked, under the rules of the contest, to agree that the contest sponsor may use your name in relation to announcing and promoting the winners of the contest. OLGC may disclose personal information where required by the operation of law or by a judicial or governmental body. 

Back To Top

**6\. Does OLGC share the information that is collected?**  
OLGC may disclose personal information to its agents, suppliers and service providers in conjunction with providing you with products and services or operating portions of the OLGC Web sites. Such entities will be required to use personal information provided solely for such purposes. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services. 

OLGC does not sell, rent or lease customer lists generated through OLGC Web sites to third parties. 

Back To Top

**7\. How can you access, edit or delete your information?**  
To delete your personal information relating to the email alert functionality currently offered by OLGC, please follow the unsubscribe process available through the link located at the bottom of the email. For Lotto Advance subscription requests, please use our online form to make changes to your personal information. If you would like to review your personal information for Lotto Advance subscription requests, call the OLGC at 1-800-387-0098. 

Back To Top

**8\. What kinds of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of your information?**  
OLGC has security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under our control. OLGC attempts to keep such information in secure facilities, protected from unauthorized access and kept only as long as is reasonably required. Only persons who have a need to know your personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy have access to the user data you choose to provide to us. OLGC has imposed strict rules on OLGC employees who have access to the databases that store user personal information or to the servers that host our services. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we make reasonable efforts to prevent such occurrences. OLGC is not liable for any use or disclosure of your personal information that is beyond our reasonable control. 

Back To Top
